# **Ankit Khare**

Seattle, Washington (open to relocation)

Career Objective: (i) Become a liaison between an organization and its developer communities to help derive the best value from their product(s).

Skills

Excellent communication skills, cross-functional team leadership, strategic thinking, proven ability to express complex ideas in simple terms, entrepreneurial mindset, collaborative attitude, strong work ethic, acuity for quickly acquiring technical knowledge and clearly expressing it to diverse audiences, excellent technical writing skills with cognizance to audience, appreciation for and attention to detail, proven success in building & nurturing communities, experience forming

strategic alliances & building ecosystem of partners, deep empathy for end-users and developers

Software Technologies

**Interpersonal Skills** 

Python, RestAPI, Git, Scikit-Learn, PyTorch, FastAI, Pandas, NumPy, SciPy, SQL

AI/ML

Solid understanding of MLOPs, strong background in Deep Learning, understanding of challenges in operationalizing ML projects, and knowledge of end-to-end ML life-cycle in production

# **Career Summary**

### **Head of Content and Developer Relations**

Abacus.AI (Formerly RealityEngines.AI)

DEVELOPER ADVOCACY / CONTENT STRATEGY

May 2020 - Jan 2023

 Built DevRel function from ground up. Typical tasks included organizing workshops, creating docs, designing product experience, writing blog posts, publishing newsletters, and creating customer demoes

Research Assistant UT-Arlington LEARN Lab

IMAGE CAPTION GENERATION USING ENCODER-DECODER-BASED ARCHITECTURES

Sep. 2018 - May 2019

- Approached image captioning in a novel way where human-like captions with better collocations and contextual inferences were observed. The state-of-the-art model (1GB size) took 48 hours to train using 2 NVIDIA P100 GPUs in parallel on GCP outperforming existing SOAs by significant margin (3.7%)
- Developed a deep learning-based parking tracker prototype and published tutorials on it

## **Head of Deep Learning R&D**

Third Insight Inc.

VISUAL SCENE UNDERSTANDING

Sep. 2019 - Dec. 2019

 Trained deep learning-based models on manually created raw data image crops for automatic aircraft inspection. Researched joint parsing modular computer vision systems for visual scene understanding

#### **Software Engineer**

Nagarro Software Pvt. Ltd.

WEB DEVELOPMENT

Apr. 2014 - Feb. 2016

- · Web Development using technologies like C#, SQL, and knockout JS. Contributed as a team player following Agile (Scrum) methodology
- One of the 3 out of 6000 students in joint-campus drive to get an offer. Impressed by **my technical, quant, and analytical scores**, Nagarro organized an on-campus hiring drive at my university
- $\bullet \ \ \, \text{Received 85\% appraisal at the end of } 1^{\text{st}} \text{ year of job and recognized as } \textbf{"star performer among Junior Associates"} \text{ in Technology } \textbf{(Starting Performer among Junior Associates)} \textbf{(Starting P$

# **Publications**

#### Show, Infer and Tell: Contextual Inference for Creative Captioning

Best Student Paper Runner-up

VISION + LANGUAGE AND DEEP LEARNING

Presented in ORAL Session BMVC 2019

- Received **Best Student Paper Award Honourable Mention.** Declared as **one of the Top 3 Papers out of more than 1000 submissions** in BMVC 2019 held at Cardiff, Wales, UK after getting selected for ORAL presentation (Acceptance Rate 4.6% with only 38 oral presentations). Paper can be found **here**. For further details, please check **Oral presentation video**
- The beauty of the work lies in the way it architects the fundamental idea that humans look at the overall image and then individual pieces of it while captioning it. **Outperformed state-of-the-art Bottom-up captioner** improving significantly in every metric on MSCOCO Karpathy split

## Abstracting Traversability to Plan the Path Better and Faster

LEARN LAB

Jan. 2020 - May 2020

PATH PLANNING AND DEEP LEARNING

• **CNNs** have never been used for finding **directional probability** from grid maps. This work demonstrates how such traversability maps can be used by RRT to plan paths faster with optimum accuracy

## **Education**

## The University of Texas at Arlington

Arlington, Tx, USA

M.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE (RESEARCH TRACK WITH FOCUS ON A.I.)

2016-2019

- Received Texas Public Education Grants (TPEG) 2018-19 for excellent research record
- Received directed study proposal from professor to invest maximum time in research topic due to strong knowledge of neural networks acquired mainly through MOOCs: cse231n from Stanford, Jeremy Howard's fast.ai, and Andrew Ng's deeplearning.ai

#### **Lovely Professional University**

Punjab, India

B.S. IN COMPUTER SCIENCE

2010-2014

- · Received 80% scholarship for the entire program on the basis of state-level engineering examination (M.P. P.E.T.)
- · Appointed by Executive Dean to develop and test enrollment portal, 'Honor's Guru' for efficient enrollment of students in classes

# **Co-**Curricular Activities

2017	<b>Video Content Creator</b> , Youtube videos and blogs for motivating people towards Data Science and Al	Youtuber
2015	First Runner-up, 'The 6th Gurgaon running & living half marathon', Results at runizen.com, Bib Number - 1006	Gurgaon, India
2015	Online Certification, 'Introduction to Nutrition and Health Part 1: Macronutrients and Overnutrition'	edX.org
2017-1	9 <b>Leader and Active member</b> , Meditation camps and seminars organized by 'Dada Bhagwan Foundation'	Dallas, USA
2010-1	6 <b>Volunteer, Cause: Children and Education</b> , 560 hours of community service for 3 different NGOs	Bhopal, India
2016-1	8 <b>President, Graduate Student Senate and Big Howdy</b> , at The University of Texas at Arlington	Arlington, Tx